But the point I want to make here is
there's an amazing
lady called, she's called Arlie
Russell
Hochschild. And I'm never comfortable
about that last name when I'm
pronouncing
it right. But she has this concept
called emotional labor.
And the point that she makes is that
an awful lot of
the jobs that people do in life, the
work involved is in having one emotion
and then
pretending that you have another
emotion.
So for example, air crew, people
who sell you soft drinks and duty
-free on the
planes, they have to be pleasant and
polite, even if people are being
obnoxious.
Lots of professions, so nurses and
doctors, they have to be friendly and
cheerful,
even if the news is terrible.
Lawyers have to not laugh when their
clients do incredibly stupid things.
So there's this work that has to be
done between the
emotions that you feel and the
emotions that you demonstrate.